A Guide to the Marianne L. Garber Collection 1780-1899
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Marianne L. Garber Collection 1780-1899
Special Collections, James Madison University
3066
This collection consists of 19 items in 1 Hollinger box and 1 oversize box.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the Library in January, 1995 by Marianne L. Garber of Timberville, VA.
Biographical/Historical Information
According to the donor, the journal was written by William Mathias Harner of McGaheysville, VA, born Nov. 24, 1823 and married Jan. 1852.
Scope and Content
This collection contains 19 items from 1780 to 1899, the majority of which are land deeds and miscellaneous legal and business documents for Rockingham and Shenandoah Counties, VA. Also included in the collection is a farm journal with one-line entries describing agricultural activities almost daily for most of the time period from August, 1847 to May, 1861.
Arrangement
Box 1: Farm Journal, Legal and Business documents, Oversize Box 1: Land deeds and Indentures.
Contents List
- 1847-1861 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Legal and Business Documents (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Debt obligation of Philip and George Pence 1815
  - Deposition on behalf of Samuel and Rebecca Fry 1854
  - July 1 Letter from Major C. Shirley to "Dear Friend" 1865
    (probably a contemporary copy)
  - Purchase list, Fred Offman to Coffman Zirkle, New Market 1877
  - Purchase list, Daniel Shirley in acc't with L.P. Henkel & Co. 1887
  - Debt obligation of John Linhoss to Charles K. Urner[?] for land 1897
  - Debt release of John Linhoss by W.P. Crickenberger 1899
  - Undated Land resurvey for David Homan
- Land Deeds and Indentures (Oversize 1)
  - Richard Campfield, "A Copy from Record" 1780
  - John Petner [Pitner], signed Beverley Randolph 1787
  - Henry Mave [Nave], signed by Henry Lee 1793
  - John & Barbara Pitner to John Nave 1794
  - Adam & Liza Pitner to John Levich 1796
  - Michael & Rachel Humble & others to John Livy 1801
  - John Homan & others to David Homan 1824
  - Gideon & Regina Pentz to Jonas Pentz 1847
  - Samuel & Rebecca Fry to Lewis Will 1854
  - Daniel Shirley to Joseph Roller 1887